你最开始开她过来的时候  我有过疑惑
I gotta say, when you first brought her in, I had my doubts.
但你的宝贝有九条命
But your little darling's got nine lives.
后轮受到严重撞击
Rear-wheel assembly took the brunt of the impact, so, uh...
是的
Yeah
传动轴  后备箱  离合  轮轴  全换了
Cv shaft, boots, joints, axle-- Replaced all of it.
没别的办法
no way around it.
大部分都是我去售后市场上采购的
I went after market on most of the parts here.
你想让我换原厂件  可以
You want me to swap in factory parts, that's fine.
但是只有使用售后市场的零件
But using after-market's the only
我们才能用保险公司的钱
way we'll keep itour air filter,
留住爱途空气过滤器
and on the insurance company's dime, okay?
什么都不如免费的好
Nothing beats free.
换了你的空气过滤器
Uh, swapped out your air filter,
加满了制动液
Topped off your fluids.
这次不用换挡风玻璃了
Didn't have to change the windshild this time.
我知道  是吧
I know, right?
我注意到你的车前端有一些
And I noticed you had some sort of gunky buildup
脏乎乎的东西
in the front end here.
一开始我不知道是什么
First I have no idea what I was looking at.
然后我记起来几个月前你撞到一头鹿的时候
Then I remembered that you had me replace that front fender
让我换过前挡泥板
a few month back when you run over that deer.
我们用蒸汽管处理了一下
We went at it with the steam hose,
为你清理干净了
cleaned it up for you.
最难的部分是喷漆
Hardest part was the paint.
蕨绿色
Fern green.
有趣的颜色
interesting tint.
-还有别的么  -就这些
- Anything else?  - That's it.
像我说的  零余平衡
Zero balance like I said.
签个字  你就可以走了
Sign here and you are good to go.
人们喜欢开玩笑
People like to joke but
但我真的很喜欢这台车
I really really like this car.
她这么结实  稳当
she's steady like hell.
我打赌你可以再开二十万英里
I'm betting you get another 200,000 miles out of her.
本尼
Hey, Benny?
你会给我什么
What would you give me for?
你是说修理报告吗
What's the blue book, you mean?
不  这辆车  你会给我什么价钱
No. What would you pay me for this car?
我并不想买车...
Well I am not really looking for..
一百美元
A hundred dollar?
五十
Fifty?
保险公司为这车的零件花费了1900美元
Insurance company just shelled out 1,900 for the parts along.
那这个价格很便宜了
That's a bargain.
你给我五十
You give me fifty bucks
这车就是你的了
and she's all yours.
你确定吗
You sure about this?
非常确定
Sure as shooting.
我去拿钱
I'll check the register.
老爸
Dad?
五十美元  你疯了么
Fifty bucks? Are you crazy?
一些地方出问题了[德语]
Ist das einigen Bereichen zum Problem gekommen?
被售出货物的问题提高了两三倍
Ausgelieferte Einheiten tauchen doppelt oder dreifach auf.
莱明格先生  这到底怎么回事
Herr Lemminge, was ist doch los?
我和技术人员谈过了  大部分认为
Ich hab mit Techniker gesprochen und gross meint
我们需要新的软件支持
wir brauchen ein neues Softwarepaket.
还有更糟的
Es gibt schlimmeres, aber
可能时间要推迟  一个
das kann verz?gern, eins
两个礼拜左右
zwei Wochen in komplizierten Merken dafür.
这和北美部门的
Das betrifft Ihr Nordamerikasektor
罗达特奎尔有关
Frau Rodarte-Quayle
不管如何都要得到一个方案来解决这个不良后果
Irgendwelche Ideen wir werden die Schaden eingrenzen.
开什么玩笑
Gotta be kidding me.
莉迪亚
Lydia
我们的解决方案
Unsere L?sung
就是用一个绕行线路通过转运中心
ist das ein Umleiter über einen Umschlagplatz,
您会用软件进行修改吧
Werden Sie über die Software überarbeiten?
这是唯一的选择
Das ist die einzige M?glichkeit.
那我们就必须这么做
Dann müssen wir so machen.
莱明先生  在我们调整软件之前
Herr Lemminge, Lassen Sie ein gro?er Plan
请您起草一个
bevor wir die neue Software umstellen k?nnen
最有效的载货清单
für ein effizientstes Ladeverzeichnis ausarbeiten,
我觉得这是个好主意
Ich finde das ist sowieso eine gute Idee.
我的天呐
Oh, christ.
我现在在工作
I am at work right now.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
给你个提醒  你有拜访者到来
This is a heads-up. You got visitors.
拜访者  什么  你是说今天
Visitors? What-- you mean today?
我是说30秒后
I mean 30 seconds.
请进
Come in.
是罗达特奎尔太太么
Ms. Rodarte-quayle?
我是汉克·施罗德探员
Agent Hank Schrader,
这位是史蒂夫·戈麦斯探员  毒品管制局的
Agent Steve Gomez, D.E.A.
我们在阿尔布开克曾经见过一面
We met briefly in Albuquerque.
是的
Uh, yes, we did.
有什么需要我帮忙的么
What can I do for you?
在那
There.
海军蓝色裤子  深蓝色短袖的那个
Navy pants, powder-blue shirt.
...集中注意力在公开的问题上
...auf ?ffensichtlichen Problemen konzentrieren.
下一步会给部门总管建议
N?chster Schritt wird vom Abteilungsleiter vorgeschlagen.,
通过沃特女士进行检测
von Frau Walter was geprüft,
在财务科备份一下
und von der Buchhaltung abgesichert.
我不可能每个礼拜都去弗洛先生那
Ich kann nicht jede Woche zum Herrn Frog gehen
并且跟他说  我们完成不了既定目标
und sagen, wir k?nnen unsere Zielvorgabe nicht einhalten.
所以  重新做一个预算
Also, Zurück zu den Voranschl?gen.
-怎么了  -他们抓住罗恩了
- Yeah?  - They got Ron.
-罗恩完了  -好的
- Ron's done.  - Okay.
不  不
No. No.
不好  麦克
Not okay, Mike.
不好
Not okay. The--
他看我的眼神
The look he just gave me
根本就不是"好"的意思  懂吗
Was the very antithesis of "Okay," Okay?
深呼吸  莉迪亚
Breathe, Lydia.
没有人会给警察招供
No one's talking to the police.
刚刚有大约14个毒品管制局探员
I just had like 14 D.E.A. agents
闯进我的办公室  对我大喊大叫
Barge into my office, screaming and yelling at me,
他们全都在仓库里
And they were swarming all over the warehouse, okay?
仓库
The warehouse!
另外  罗恩是我的人
Besides, Ron was my guy.
记得么  我没有其他的人了
Remember? I don't have a guy anymore.
罗恩搞定保安  拉出原料桶  开车
Ron fixed security and pulled the barrels and drive the truck
你不能指望我做这些事情
You can't expect me to do that stuff.
我是说  现实一点
I mean, let's be realistic.
麦克  这太疯狂了
Mike, this is crazy.
我会给你派个新人
I'll send a new guy.
你疯了
You are crazy.
我的车有将近五百马力
My car almost has 500 horsepower.
-绝对无敌  -马力不是一切
- It would totally smoke--  - horsepower isn't everything.
你不知道么
Don't you know that?
你还得考虑阻力  扭矩  悬挂
You have to factor in drag and torque and suspension
以及车的重量
And weight of the car.
听着还有一个你没有考虑到的因素
And listen one more factor you are not thinking about
驾驶员的经验
The experience of the driver.
-这个我肯定赢你  -得了吧
- And I totally got you there.  - Please. Please.
-我赢你了  -你开车就像个老头
- I got you.  - You drive like a geezer.
真的么  我开车像个老头
Really? I drive like a gee--
告诉我  老头能玩原地转圈么  我觉得不能
Tell me, can a geezer do donuts? I don't think so.
扯淡  你没玩过原地转圈
Bullshit you ever did donuts.
注意你的语言
Whoa. Watch your language.
-还有  我确实做过  -真的
- And, yes, I did.  - Seriously?
真的  如果你向我表示
Yes, seriously. And if you show me
哪怕一丁点的尊重  也许我会教你
Just a modicum of respect, maybe I'll teach you.
-真的么  真的么  -不
- Yeah? Yes?  - No.
-不  我不会  我收回这句话  -会的
- No, I won't. I take that back. - Yes. Yes. No--
-就是个玩笑  -你说了你会的
- Just a joke. I'm just--  - you're saying yes.
不  不  不  那是开玩笑
No! No, no. That was kidding.
-我们没握手约定  不  -你会的  会的
- We didn't shake on it. No.  - Yes. Yes.
-我们现在约定了  -这不算
- We are now.  - That doesn't count!
我知道你不同意
I know you don't approve.
但是我的车
But mine...
我们可以说是送给我自己的生日礼物
we'll call it a birthday present to myself.
儿子的...
And junior's...
人们会觉得
People will just chalk that up
我耳根软
As me being softy.
再说了
And beside,
我又没有买下来
I didn't actually buy either one.
都是租的  所以不会有破绽
They're both leases. So it all fits our story.
明白吗
Okay?
而且我们也付得起
We can afford it now. Hmm?
你又开始制毒了
You back at it.
是啊
Well, yeah.
得把那损失的60万赚回来
We have to make up that 600,000 we lost.
你觉得寄宿学校怎么样
What do you think about boarding school?
寄宿学校
Boarding school?
让谁去  咱儿子
For who-- for junior?
北亚利桑那有所学校
You know there is a place in north arizona,
全国排名前十
and it's supposed to be one of the top ten in the country.
他还有一年就读大学了
He's a year away from college.
现在转学干嘛
Why on earth would we do that?
我只是
I just...
为他们着想
just thinking about the kids.
那霍莉呢
Mmm. Holly, too?
你准备把她送去哪
Where are we sending our eight-month-old?
维和部队吗
Peace corps?
不  我只是觉得
No. I just...
一个新环境
A new environment
没准对他们要好一点
might be good for them.
什么意思
What does that mean?
他们现在的环境怎么了
What's wrong with their environment?
斯凯勒
Skyler...
现在的环境怎么了
What's wrong with their environment?
没什么
Nothing.
我知道过去几周比较难熬
Listen, I know this last few weeks have been rough.
汉克被人威胁
The threat to Hank
还有贝内克的事情
and this whole thing with Beneke.
但是从现在开始
But there's absolutely nothing
你绝对不用再害怕什么了
for you to be afraid of anymore, okay?
从现在开始高枕无虞  我保证
Clear sailing from here on out. I promise.
我希望我们可以
You know, I want us to try
重新开始向前看
and start looking forward to things again.
比如说  我的生日
Speaking of which, my birthday.
我不知道
I don't know--
不知道你已经计划了什么
I don't know what you have planned,
鉴于最近发生了那么多事
and with everything that's been going on lately,
你完全没有想过的话  我也理解
I'd understand if you haven't even given it a thought.
但我觉得
But I think,
对我们所有人来说
a little celebration might be good.
小小庆祝一下也无妨
For all of us.
你知道的  生日派对
You know, a birthday party.
你觉得呢
What do you think?
好吧
Okay.
然后  容我大胆再说一句
And maybe, if I may be so bold,
做个巧克力糖衣生日蛋糕吧
Chocolate cake with chocolate icing?
生活很美好  斯凯勒
Life is good, Skyler.
谢谢
Thank you.
老妈  你忘了点什么吧
Hey, mom, you forgot something.
老爸的熏肉
Dad's bacon.
没关系  我自己来就好
That's okay. I can do it.
不行  必须老妈来
No. Mom has to.
好吧  这是传统
Well, it is sort of a tradition.
瞧这个  霍莉
Watch this, Holly.
看看你老妈在做什么
Watch what she does with bacon.
快看  快看
Watch it. Watch it.
她在干嘛
What is she doing?
在干嘛
What is she doing? Hmm?
那个"1"太小了吧
That's a pretty small "1"
是有点
Kind of is.
有点小
Just a little.
这就对了
Ah, now you're talking.
-不  不能这样  -好样的
- No. No. - Good move.
不  不  这样挺好的
No. No, no, no. It's good.
很好  家人同心协力
Very good. Family teamwork.
为对方做出牺牲  这很重要
Making sacrifices. Very important.
-生日快乐  老爸  -谢了
- Happy birthday, dad. - Thank you, buddy.
要来点吗
You want some?
他真的很有一手  对吧
Guy's some piece of work, isn't he?
古斯塔沃·福林
就剩半张脸  长眠于六尺之下
Six feet under and half of face,
依旧把我们耍得团团转
he's still screwing with us.
下一步怎么办
So, what's next?
我也不知道
Oh, I don't know.
麦德罗那边看起来很奇怪
This madrigal thing seems hinky, though, you know?
我们知道这个人远在德国
We got burgermeister meisterburger over here in germany,
彼得·舒勒
罗恩·福伦诺尔
而这个人在5000英里以外
And 5,000 miles away, you got this guy.
中间一定有什么人
There's gotta be someone in the middle, you know?
我们还没查到
Someone we're missing.
那个叫莉迪亚的女人呢
What about that, uh, Lydia what's-her-name?
那个管仓库的大眼美女
You know, lady banjo eyes at the warehouse?
绝对不可能
In this world? No way.
太保守  太正常
Too uptight. Too together.
可能吧
Maybe.
她连鞋都穿错了
She was wearing mismatched shoes.
能有多正常
How together can she be?
先生们  福林的案子查得怎么样了
Gentlemen, how goes it with Fring?
困难重重
You know, just, uh, working through the grief.
还要多久才能结案
How soon before you submit a final?
我们还在查
Well, we've been kicking around some ideas.
如果你几周前问我
Had you asked me that a couple of weeks ago,
-我会说马上就能结案了  -但是呢
- I'd have said this was just a mop-up job, but... - But?
福林手下
福林的手下没有一个人松口
Well, no one on Fring's crew is talking to us.
不管我们怎么逼  都不肯透露一个字
I mean, not a peep, no matter how hard we squeeze.
就好像是有人要他们闭嘴一样
Which makes it likely thut there keeping them in line.
我们怀疑是这个人  迈克尔·厄门绍特
Our money is on this guy-- Michael Ehrmantraut.
他在福林手下主管企业安全
He's Fring's head of "Corporate" Security.
这人可很难搞定
He's a definite hard case.
我们现在要重点关注他
Now, we're gonna stay on him.
已经派人去监视他了
We're putting together a surveillance team as we speak.
还有一件事
Okay? The other thing is--
可能与案子没关联
This may be unrelated,
蓝色冰毒又回到市面上了
but, the blue math is make a little comeback.
-你告诉他  -虽然量不多
- Tell him. Yeah. - Some small amounts on the street-side pulls.
但实验室的人说是一样的货
Lab's telling us it's the same stuff.
这可能是以前的存货
I mean, it could be old inventory leaking out,
或者是有人又开始重新制毒了
Or it could be somebody's rebooting,
用福林的毒师  重操旧业
Using Fring's former cooks set up a new operation.
我以为已经找到福林的毒师了
I thought we had Fring's cooks--
那些被烧死在实验室的人
The unsubs in the lab fire.
没准儿其中一个就是你要找的海森堡
Thought maybe one of them was your Heisenberg.
有可能  我也不知道
Yeah. Maybe. I don't know.
就像我刚才说的  疑点还很多
Like I said, there's stilll lot of questions.
戈麦斯探员  能回避一下吗
Agent gomez, could you give us a moment?
汉克  我必须说
Hank, I gotta say,
你这个案子办的太棒了
Your work here has been stellar.
表现杰出
Really first rate.
谢谢  长官
Thank you, sir.
所以我觉得是该让你更上一层楼的时候了
So much so that I'm wondering if it's time you made a change.
你知道的  我要回艾尔帕索
You know, I have to get back to El Paso.
这里需要一个人来接管
This office needs an A.S.A.C.,
我觉得应该从本部门的人里提拔
and I'm thinking we should be promoting from within.
如果你申请的话
If you were to put in an application,
我推荐你  这位置就是你的
and I recommend that you do, you will get the job.
我相信这里如果由你领导
I have no doubt this D.O. would be well served
一定会很好的
with you at the helm.
这真是...
Wow. That's, uh...
我都不知道该说什么了
I'm not sure what to say.
这对你来说是个飞跃
It's a big step up.
但也有挑战
It's not without it's headaches.
政治方面的事可能需要点时间来适应
The politics may take some getting used to.
加上你要负责起这里所有的案子
Plus, you'd be overseeing every case in the office,
所以要重新安排你的时间
So you'd need to reassign all your day-to-days,
包括福林这个案子
Fring included.
虽然我不想失去你这么好的探员
Much as I hate losing a good field man,
但如果你接下这份工作  就必须接受
That's the job, and you need to be okay with it.
你觉得呢  汉克
What do you say, Hank?
愿意接受吗
You want it?
如果我拒绝我老婆应该会杀了我
Considering my wife would murder me if I said "No"...
我愿意
Yeah. I want it.
-恭喜你  -谢谢
- Congratulations. -Thank you.
你能不能
Can you, uh,
替我收尾
Finish up for me?
今天是我生日
It's-- it's my birthday.
-是吗  -是的
- Oh, yeah? - Yeah.
可能有个生日派对
I probably have a birthday party
在等我  所以...
waiting for me, you know, so...
好的  没问题
Uh, yeah. Cool. Yeah, no problem.
生日快乐
Hey, uh, happy birthday.
谢谢
Thanks.
老爸
Hey, dad.
你妈妈人呢
Where's your mom?
在厨房
Uh, kitchen.
今天怎么安排
So, what's the plan?
汉克和玛丽在路上
Um, Hank and Marie are on their way,
晚饭吃烤鸡和土豆泥
roast chicken and potatoes for dinner,
甜点是坚果冰激凌
rocky road for dessert,
还有你要求的巧克力蛋糕
And, uh, chocolate cake, as requested.
你怎么了
What's up?
我
Me?
没事啊
Nothing.
你对我升职都不是很兴奋
Thought you'd be more jazzed about the new job.
不  我当然兴奋
No! What-- no! I am!
-宝贝  我以你为荣  -好的
- Baby, I'm so proud of you. - Yeah, yeah
-抱歉  -我相信你  别出车祸就行
- Sorry, sorry. - I believe you. Just don't kill us here.
玛丽  你这几天一直闷闷不乐
Marie, you've been moping around the last few days.
玛丽
Marie?
怎么回事
What's up?
-玛丽  说吧  -对不起
- Marie, come on. - I'm sorry. I...
我对别人保证过不说
I made a promise to someone.
对谁保证
To who?
-谁  -你姐夫
- Who? - Your brother-in-law.
你至少给我点暗示吧
Are you gonna give me a hint at least?
跟"不忠"有关  我只能说这么多
It involves infidelity. That's all I'm gonna say.
见鬼  我就知道
Oh, shit. I knew it.
知道什么  你知道什么
Knew what? What did you-- what did you know?
我虽然不确定  但纸包不住火
Well, I mean, I didn't know it, but I wouldn't, saying it forever.
沃尔特不是有第二部手机吗
Walt's second cell phone, you know?
抱歉了  宝贝  但这事我比你早知道很久了
Sorry, babe, but I was way ahead of you on this one.
比我早知道是吧
Way ahead of me. Oh.
不忠的不是沃尔特
Well, it wasn't Walt.
是斯凯勒
Skyler?
不可能
No way.
终于见面了
Hey! There she is!
-你好  伙计  -欢迎  进来吧
- Hey, buddy. Yeah. - Welcome. Come on in.
生日快乐
Happy birthday.
我在中央车道开着  时速60英里
I'm in the center lane going about 60,
我必须要离开那里
and I had no choice just tear butt out of there.
中央车道  不能久待  只能用来掉头
于是一踩油门  太牛了
Just bwaaa! So sweet.
没错  高速路巡警也不是吃素的
Yeah, highway patrol's gonna be sweet on it too.
他们会把一个月的罚单都罚给你
Gonna get their ticket quota in a month.
你会帮我的吧  汉克叔叔
You'll help me out, right, uncle Hank,
毒品管制局现在都归你管了
Now that you run the D.E.A.?
当然  帮洗车业百万富翁的富二代侄子
Oh, yeah. For my spoiled brat car wash millionaire nephew?
当然  我会给你找个海景牢房
Sure. I'll make sure you get a cell with a view.
好的
All right.
-我要走了  -好的
- Well, I'm outta here. - Okay.
-生日快乐  -谢谢你
- Happy birthday. - Thank you, buddy.
-再次恭喜  汉克叔叔  -谢谢
- Congratulations again, uncle Hank. - Thanks.
-稍后见  -好的
- I'll see y'all later. - All right.
-再见  儿子  -玩的愉快
- Bye, son. - Have fun.
-悠着点开  好吗  -我很小心的
- Drive safely, okay? - I do.
-开慢点  -休想
- Slow down.  - Never.
你们的车真是酷啊  沃尔特
A hell of a couple cars there, Walt.
亲爱的  我下次过生日
Honey, for my next birthday,
会让沃尔特给我开张支票
I'm gonna take a page here from Walt
然后去买架喷气飞机
and buy myself a jet plane.
也许我做的过了点
Well, maybe I overdid it .
但新的租车利率
But with these new lease rates--
实在太诱人了
I mean, they're mighty attractive.
晚餐很棒  斯凯勒
Great dinner, Skyler.
你土豆泥做的真棒
Those were some bad-ass whipped potatoes, I tell you.
你一定要告诉我怎么把小块打碎
You have to tell me how you get all the lumps out.
你怎么做到的
How do you do that?
土豆捣碎器
A potato ricer.
捣碎器啊
A ricer.
你不是手工做的吗
You don't hand mash?
不是
No.
-那么...  -天啊
- Well, uh... - Boy, it has...
这一年真不容易啊
It has been quite a year, huh?
你们是否知道
Do you know that, uh,
几乎在整整一年前
It's almost exactly a year ago
我拿到了诊断报告
that I got my diagnosis?
-上帝啊  是吗  -是的
- Jesus. Yeah, right? - Yeah.
-感觉好像很久以前  -是啊
- Seems like longer, doesn't it? - Yeah. No. It's, uh...
一年前的明天
One year ago tomorrow.
我五十岁生日的第二天
Day after my 50th.
老实说  我没想过自己能坚持到今天
Honestly, I never thought I could make it this far.
癌症和手术
The cancer and surgery
还有汉克中枪的事
and Hank being shot-- it just...
往事不堪回首
So many dark days.
还有玛丽的"真心话枕头"  记得吗
There's Marie's talking pillow. Remember that?
第一季中情结
我觉得...
It was...  It is...
我当时不想接受任何治疗
Boy, I didn't want to get any treatment.
我想我可能太害怕了
I think I was too scared
或太愤怒了
or too angry or...
我不知道  我就想放弃
I don't know. I just wanted to quit.
但你们帮我渡过了难关
But you guys-- you got me through it somehow.
让我坚持下来
Kept me going.
而且这样的事一再发生
And that happened again and again and again.
有那么几次
I mean, there were times
我以为我肯定完蛋了
when I was sure I was done for.
但某人
But then someone
或某事
or something
最后总是帮我脱险
would come through for me.
上帝啊  而且斯凯勒
God. And Skyler-- I can't--
亲爱的  还记得第一周化疗吗
Honey, remember that first week of chemotherapy?
晚上在浴室地板上
That night on the bathroom floor?
你对我说的话
What you said to me?
我当时很难受
I was so sick.
第一次去化疗很痛苦
It was rough going at first.
但斯凯勒
But Skyler--
她陪着我  当然了
She was right there, of course,
把湿毛巾敷在我额头上
Putting wet washcloths on my forehead.
她给我唱歌
And she's singing to me.
就这样一次次继续
And this would go on and on,
日复一日
Day after day.
我记得我躺在浴室的地板上
And I remember I was lying on the floor of the bathroom,
因为瓷砖感觉很舒服  很凉爽
Because the tile felt nice and cool, you know?
我的头枕着斯凯勒的腿
And my head was in Skyler's lap,
我问她
And I was just asking her
这事还有尽头吗
if this could all be over.
那时太困难了
It was too hard. It was...
我就想快点结束...
I just want it to stop...
斯凯勒  水不是很冷吗
Skyler, isn't that freezing?
泳池派对哦
Whoa. Hey-o. Pool party.
你在干什么  斯凯勒
What are you doing, Skyler?
她在干什么  沃尔特
What is she doing? Walt?
斯凯勒  该出来了
Hey, uh, sky, maybe it's time to get out now.
你觉得呢
What do you think?
斯凯勒  汉克在问你话呢
Skyler,  Hank asked you a question.
你快出来...  斯凯勒
You need to get out n-- Skyler!
她会出来的  对吧
She's gonna come up, right?
一定要上来
She has to.
斯凯勒  快出来
Skyler, you need to get out.
我的上帝啊
Oh, my god.
好吧
Wha-- okay.
好的  应该是这个...
Okay. It's gotta be...
不对
Nope.
别这样  到底要我怎么样
Come on! How am I supposed to...
等等
Wait.
等等  你是谁
Wait, wait. Who are you?
我是来拿货的  东西在哪儿...
I'm the-- I'm the guy. So where's the--
等等  等等
Hold on. Hold on.
谁派你来的
Who sent you?
谁派我来的  你觉得是谁
Who sent me? Who do you think?
别绕弯子  是我在问你
No. I'm asking you.
麦克
Mike
你所说的这个麦克
And this Mike person--
他姓什么
What's his last name?
女士  我刚从新墨西哥州坐飞机来
Lady, I just got off a plane from New Mexico,
我还有900英里的返程车要开
and I got a 900-mile drive back.
如果中间不停  一共就是14小时
That's 14 hours if I don't stop.
所以越早交货  越早搞定
He sooner we do this, the sooner it's done.
他姓厄门绍特
Uh, Ehrmantraut.
好了吗  满意了
Okay? Satisfied?
对不起  但我不会为自己的谨慎道歉
Sorry, but I'm not gonna apologize for being careful.
最近发生了这么多事  我只知道
With all that's been happening around here, for all I knew,
你就是他们派到学校里
you were one of those undercover people
做卧底的吧
they send into high schools.
所以我天天得担心
So, yeah, I'll take paranoid any day
别被关进大牢里
if we're getting ganged by prison guards.
没错  东西在哪里
Oh, no doubt. So, uh, where's the--
上面  号码是22356
up there. Number 22356.
我从库房记录里删掉的那个
That's the one I erased from the inventory,
肯定没错
so it has to be that one.
能弄下来吧
Can you reach it?
有升降机就行
With a forklift.
这儿有吧
You got one?
停停停  刹住
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait! Stop!
天呐
Oh, my god. Oh, my god.
怎么了
What?
拜托  怎么会这样
Please tell me that's not what I think it is.
过去有过这种情况吗
Has anything like this ever happened before?
没  怎么会呢
No. No, of course not.
从没过  就是
No, no. I just...
我们之间出了些问题
she and I are having some issues.
明白  我多少也有些耳闻
Yeah, yeah. I, uh-- I might've heard a little bit about that.
这事吧  玛丽也没怎么说
Oh, right. I mean, hey, look, Marie didn't go into detail.
反正没那么说
You know, said that,
怎么说呢  你们两口子
You know, you guys were...
是有点问题
ha-having some issues.
那你准备怎么办
So, uh, what's the next move?
找人说说总会好些
Be good to talk someone.
-也是  -是吧
- Oh, I agree. - Yeah.
我头回碰到这种烂事
Well, I'm gonna get on that first thing.
其实玛丽也搞过  叫大伟
There's Marie's guy, Dave.
她跟那厮好像还挺动情的
She seems really happy with him.
而且还不是因为
Not that Marie's an advertisement
她装做神经兮兮的傻娘们儿
for advanced mental health or anything.
所以嘛
You know...
我就是想不出她怎么这么当回事
I just had no idea she was taking it this hard.
瞧你这生日
Some birthday, huh?
她想休息了
She's gonna try and get some sleep.
那就好
Oh, okay.
怎么回事
What was that?
搞不明白
I don't know.
她真是要...
I mean was she trying...
不会  怎么可能在泳池里自杀  不可能
No, not in a swimming pool. No.
还当我们的面  绝不可能
With all of us there? No, I don't think so.
不过我们哥俩
But, uh, we both, uh,
还是觉得
think that...
她得找人说出来
she should talk to someone.
我给你大伟的电话
I'm gonna get you Dave's number.
好
Okay.
沃尔特  听我说
Listen, Walt, I--
我必须得清楚
I can't help but sense
你和斯凯勒之间
that there may be some issues
到底出了什么问题
between you and Skyler.
虽然说是你们自己的事
None of our business, of course.
汉克  我不知道
And, Hank, I don't know if you
-你是不是说了  -他知道
- picked up on any of-- - He knows--
他知道我知情
He knows I know.
两口子  难免的
These things happen in a marriage,
可终究都能挽回
but it isn't unfixable.
我还是觉得
I think what would be great is if
你们俩最好还是能
you two had some space
心平气和地处理好这件事
to work through this stuff.
所以说
So--
过去的就让它过去
and keep an open mind here.
孩子我们先照顾一段时间好吗
What if we took the kids for a while?
-照顾孩子  -对啊
- Took the kids? - Absolutely.
我们先帮你们看几天  多久都成
We'll look after them for a day or two, or however long,
你和斯凯勒
and leave you and Skyler
好好过过二人世界
to look after each other.
玛丽  你真好
Uh, that's very generous of you, Marie,
不过我还是觉得没用
but I-- I just don't see how that's a solution.
而且我觉得
And-- I mean--
那兄妹俩还是挺难弄的
besides, Junior and Holly-- that's a lot of work.
怎么会呢
No, it isn't.
老大那么懂事
Junior's independent,
而且我那小侄女
and my niece is only the easiest,
天底下哪儿有那么乖的啊
she is a baby that was ever born.
-他们会给我们带来很多乐趣  对吧  -对  没错
- It'll be fun, right? - Yeah. Yeah. No, yeah.
必须的
Absolutely. Yeah.
这就对了
It's a good idea.
绝对是个好主意
I think it's a great idea.
对你俩再好不过了
Just the thing for both of you.
玛丽
Marie,
这是你的主意吗
This idea-- was it yours?
其实是斯凯勒的
Actually, it was Skyler's.
她真心希望如此  沃尔特
She really needs this, Walt.
明白了
Yep.
奶瓶我给玛丽了
I gave Marie bottles.
他俩路上会买些尿片
They'll stop and pick up diapers on their way.
我也和儿子通了电话
I spoke with Junior on the phone,
说了半天之后
and after much discussion,
他也答应明天就搬过去  先取些衣服
he agreed to swing by tomorrow, pick up some clothes.
满意了吧  让俩孩子远离是非之地
And so, voila, the kids are out of this environment.
真巧
What a coincidence.
我知道你没睡
I know you're awake.
你到底想干什么  不能说说吗
What was that about, can you explain it?
我不愿孩子们再待在这里
I don't want the children here anymore.
不安全
It isn't safe.
斯凯勒  这我们都说多少次了
Skyler, we have talked about this repeatedly.
-从来就没...-没安全过
-There's never been... -Been more safe.
"从没"吗
"Never been"?
几个星期前  有人闯来家里
A couple weeks ago, a man was coming to this house
来杀我们  来灭门
to kill us, to murder your entire family.
你藏在地缝里乱喊乱叫
You were in the crawlspace, screaming.
可我搞定了  没事了
And I dealt with him. It's over.
哪有
It is not.
你又开始搞你那冰毒了
You're right back in the meth business again.
不一样了  现在我说了算
This is different. Now I'm running things.
吹吧  既然你说了算
So wait. Now that you're in charge,
那怎么还没有风平浪静
it's what- it's gonna be smooth sailing from here on out?
难道没有吗
I don't see it isn't, why not?
斯凯勒  一切都在我掌控之中
I keep the work at work, Skyler,
绝对不会对你和孩子有什么影响
And nothing will ever impact you or the kids.
你理解不了  沃尔特  别说大话
You don't know that. You can't make that promise, Walt.
可我保证  古斯·福林死了
I can promise you that gus fring is dead.
他才是我们的威胁
And he was the threat and he was the danger.
我看你才是威胁
I thought you were the danger.
你水池里搞那出就为这个
Is that what your pool stunt was about?
就是要保护孩子不受我的威胁吗
Trying to protect my children from me?
不是就要...
Not just...
我现在也不干净了
There's blood on my hands too.
什么不干净  贝内克吗
What blood? Beneke?
他因为我  现在躺在医院
He's in the hospital because of me.
-说什么  -因为就是我干的
-No. -Because it was I did.
斯凯勒  你不能为这事自责终生
Skyler, you can't beat yourself up over this thing.
行了  你又没想着伤害别人
Please. You didn't set out to hurt anybody.
不过是个失误  事情没做好罢了
You made a mistake, and things got out of control,
终究是事出无奈  为了保护家人
But you did what you had to do to protect your family.
我也觉得遗憾  但你又不能成了坏人
And I'm sorry. That doesn't make you a bad person,
都是人嘛
It makes you a human being.
去  沃尔特  别说了
Stop it, Walt. Just stop.
我不想听你那套狗屁逻辑
I don't need to hear any of your bullshit rationales.
现在我也有份
I'm in it now.
把我牵扯进去了  可是我不想
I'm compromised. But I won't--
我就是不想让俩孩子生活在
I will not have my children living in a house
这大毒窝里
where dealing drugs
生活在伤天害理的罪恶之家
and hurting people and killing people
不想让他们遭到天谴
Is shrugged off as "Shit happens."
你我遭报应也就罢了
We're back at it? Fine.
可俩孩子不应该待在这里  就这话
But the kids stay away, and that's that.
就这话  什么意思
That's that? That's what?
就是不能让他们住在这里
I got them out of this house.
那就能混在小姨家吗
To a sleepover at their aunt and uncle's?
那待个几天
They spend a day or two,
让儿子整宿看片子  然后呢
Junior stays up late watching movies, and then what happens?
-走着瞧吧  -没门  我告诉你怎么办吧
We'll see. No, I'll tell you what happens.
孩子回家  回这里来
They come home, to this house.
回到疼他们的父母身边
To their parents who love them.
休想  绝不能让你的烂事影响他们
No. I will not let our business endanger them.
-要我说多少遍  影响不到他们  -我说了不行
- How many times do I have to say that they are not in... - I said no.
我对天发誓  绝不让他们回来
I swear to god, I won't have them back here.
你凭什么能阻止孩子回来
What are you gonna do to stop it?
想法设法  竭尽全力
Whatever it takes. Everything in my power.
比如呢  具体点
Like what? I mean, specificly.
你下一步计划
What is your next move?
下一步  兴许就是自残
My next move is maybe I hurt myself.
你想清楚点  有的是时间
Make it clear we need more time.
让汉克和玛丽看看我们的矛盾
Let Hank and Marie see we're still struggling.
胡说  也就是你在闹矛盾
No, more like you're still struggling.
所以也许下次  我就得让你默认
So maybe next time, I have you committed.
把你送进精神疗养院
Put you in some inpatient facility
而我一个人来照顾孩子
while I take care of the kids myself.
你是想这样吗
Is that what you want?
要不我索性脖子上多几道伤痕
So then maybe I show up with bruises on my neck,
把自己的眼睛搞得发青
give myself a black eye,
说是你发现我有外遇
say that you beat me
于是把我给打了一顿
when you found out about my lover.
我懂了
I see.
原来你想把泰德也牵扯进来
So you want to involve Ted?
那会很有意思
Oh, well, that'll be fun,
给警察提供第一手资料
bringing the police up to speed on all of that.
可告诉我们年仅16岁的儿子  他爸有家暴
But how much fun is that by telling our 16-year-old son
该多有意思呢
that his father is a wife-beater.
这计划也不尽如人意  还有什么法子
Also not a very good plan. What else you got?
我可以送儿子到很远的地方去上学
I could send Junior away to school.
那我们会这样告诉他
Oh. Now here's the conversation:
"亲爱的  我知道你高中还有一年才上完"
"So honey, I know you've got one year left in the high school,
"可我希望你能放下一切"
but I would love it so much if you would drop everything,
"抛下你所有的朋友"
leave all your friends behind,
"去上亚利桑那州的寄宿学校"
and go to boarding school in Arizona."
还有其它想法吗
You have any other ideas?
我还没听到一个解决你问题的方法
Because I'm not hearing a solution to your problem.
你准备怎样让孩子们摆脱这个恶劣的环境
How are you going to save our kids from this terrible environment?
-我不...  -你有什么打算
- I don't...  - What are you gonna do?
你准备逃去欧洲吗
Are you gonna run off to France?
你准备拉上帘子换上锁吗
Are you gonna close the curtains, change the locks?
开玩笑  别天真了  斯凯勒
This is a joke. Come on, Skyler.
你想跟我作对吗  你想带走我的孩子们吗
You wanna take me on? You wanna take away my children?
-你有什么计划  -不知道
- What's the plan? - I don't know!
这是我想到最好的办法了  别逼我好吗
This is the best I could come up with, okay?
孩子们离开这里
I-- I will count every minute
离开你的每一分钟
that the kids are away from here,
我都当做是一种胜利
away from you, as a victory.
可你说得对
But you're right.
这个计划太失败了
It's a bad plan.
我没有你的魔力  沃尔特
I don't have any of your magic, Walt.
我不知道该怎么做
I don't know what to do.
我是个胆小鬼
I'm a coward.
我不能去报警
I-- I can't go to the police.
我无法停止帮你洗钱
I can't stop laundering your money.
我没能力把你赶出这栋房子
I can't keep you out of this house.
甚至连把你赶下床都做不到
I can't even keep you out of my bed.
我只能等
All I can do is wait.
就是这样  这是唯一可行的选择
That's it. That's the only good option.
静观其变
Hold on,
伺机而动
bide my time,
继续等待
and wait.
等待什么  你在等什么
Wait for what? What are you waiting for?
等癌症复发
For the cancer to come back.
喂
Yeah?
好
Okay.
别紧张  我这就来
Just relax. I'm coming.
你看  你说这是什么情况
Look at that! You tell me what that looks like.
如果毒品管制局在跟踪她的货品
If the D.E.A.'s tracking her barrels,
那我们的供货方就已经完了
there goes our precursor connection.
完了  告诉你们  这段日子
That's done. And I'm telling yo these days,
要找到新的甲胺卖家的机会渺茫
chances of getting a new methylamine hook-up is rare, man.
就跟找独角兽和龙一样不现实
It's like bigfoot. Like unicorn-rare.
孩子  你太闹心了
Kid, it's just-- you're giving me heartburn here.
桶底下装了定位装置
G.P.S. on the bottom of the barrel.
他们为什么不装在里面掩人耳目呢
Why didn't they put it inside where nobody would see it?
装在里面就湿了
Look, it's inside, it gets wet.
这些机器的发明是用来装在车底的
They made these things to put under cars.
所以是防水的
They can get wet.
即便是警用标准  这也太粗糙了
Even by cop standards this is sloppy.
那其它的桶
And the other barrels--
外面也有跟踪器吗
They have trackers on the outside too?
不知道  可能吧
I don't know. Probably.
-你没排查其它的吗  -没
- You didn't check any of the other barrels? - No.
她说我们只能拿那一桶
But that's the only one we could've taken, according to her.
我们一发现这玩意儿  她就发神经了
Once we spotted it, she freaked out,
我把桶放回去  我们就跑了
I put the barrel back, and we F.O.'d.
我问你
Let me ask you something.
发现这个的人
The person who spotted this--
是你还是她
Was it you or was it her?
是莉迪亚  她先看到的
Lydia. She saw it first.
好
Okay.
她死定了
She's dead.
等等  怎么了
Wait, wait, wait. What?
是莉迪亚安装的  不是警察
Lydia planted this thing, not the cops.
她自认为如果伪装成
She's thinking if she makes it look
她的库存被盯上了
like her inventory's being watched
那我们就会放过她  然后另找别家
that we'll leave her alone and take our business elsewhere.
她想的没错
And she's right.
我们的确会另找别家
We will be taking our business elsewhere,
就在我们把她抛尸地沟之后
right after we leave her alone at the ditch.
等等  毒品管制局没查她的货
But wait, hey, if the D.E.A.'s not tracking her stuff,
那算是好事  对吧
that's a good thing, right?
我们只要告诉她
I mean, all we gotta do is tell her to,
让她别胡折腾  只管供货
you know, cut the crap and keep the methylamine coming.
你没我了解她
You don't know this woman like I do.
我之前就有机会灭了她  结果我放了她一马
I had a chance to deal with this before, and I gave her a pass.
这就是怜香惜玉的后果
That's what I get for being sexist.
让一下
Now, if you'll excuse me...
麦克  能不能...
Mike, you can't just...
她是我们的供货商  我们需要她
Look, that's our precursor. We need her.
孩子  如果我们必须放慢速度  那就顺其自然
Kid, if we have to ramp down for a while, so be it.
和一个会害我们被捕或送死的疯子共事很危险
It beats working with a lunatic who's gonna get us arrested or killed.
听着  我看她不疯
Look, she didn't seem crazy to me, you know?
只是有点紧张
She just seemed, like, uptight.
现在你也怜香惜玉了
And now you're being sexist.
相信我  这个女人该死
Trust me,this woman deserves to die
和其他我认识的男人没差别
as much as any man I've ever met.
不  等等
No. Wait!
别急
Just wait.
如果真是警察干的呢
What if this really was the cops, you know?
-如果你错怪她了呢  -不会错的
- And what if you're wrong about her? - I'm not wrong.
如果错怪了呢
But what if you are?
杰西  我会考虑你的担忧
Jesse, your misgivings have been duly noted.
现在给我闪开
Now move away from me.
不行  得投票表决
No. This is a voting thing.
-不好  -我投票表决这事需要投票表决
- I don't think so. - I vote it's a voting thing.
怀特老师  帮帮忙  怎么样
Mr. White, weigh in here, would you?
你怎么看
What do you think?
怀特老师
Mr. White?
不管怎样  甲胺供给必须源源不断
The methylamine keeps flowing, no matter what.
我们速度不会减慢
We are not ramping down.
我们才开始
We're just getting started.
没有任何事能阻止我们前行
Nothing stops this train.
休想
Nothing.
等等  怀特老师  等一下
Hey, yo, Mr. White. Hold up.
我只想说我喜欢你的主意
I just wanted to say I liked your idea.
非常...
You know, it's pretty, uh...
我觉得很行得通
I think it's the way to go.
你之前说那天是你的生日  所以...
You said it was your-- your birthday, so...
收据我留在盒子里了
I left the receipt in the box
方便你换
just in case you wanna exchange it.
不管怎样  祝你生日快乐
Anyway, hey, happy birthday.
我今天顺道去了汉克和玛丽家
I, uh, stopped by Hank and Marie's.
儿子还在不停问情况
Junior is still asking, "What is going on?"
真是打破沙锅问到底
Nonstop, very insistently.
不过没事
But everything is okay.
他们在看《料理鼠王》
They're watching Ratatouille.
很有意思
It's very sweet.
你好吗
How are you?
还会有更多的钱入账
There's gonna be some more money coming in soon.
没关系吧
Is that okay?
没关系
Fine.
很好
Good.
那...
So...
睡觉吗
Coming to bed?
我想给你看点东西
I wanna show you something.
看到那块表了吗
See that watch?
是份生日礼物
It's a birthday present.
送我这块表的人
The person who gave me this present
之前也想让我死
wanted me dead too.
就在不久前
Not that long ago,
他把枪架在我眉中
He pointed a gun right between my eyes,
就在这里
right here,
还威胁要杀了我
and he threatened to kill me.
他后来对我改观了  斯凯勒
He changed his mind about me, Skyler,
你也会对我改观的
and so will you.